moneywise.co.uk 2019-04-03

# Moneywise Privacy Policy | Moneywise

## General information

Moneywise takes the issue of privacy very seriously and we are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. It is our policy to take all necessary steps to ensure that Personal Information held by us is processed fairly and lawfully in accordance with the requirements of all applicable legislation including the General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR). We will take all necessary steps to implement this policy. All our employees and data processors who have access to Personal Information are obliged to respect the confidentiality of your Personal Information.

This policy sets out how we will treat your personal information. If you have any concerns regarding this policy you should contact the Data Protection Officer at [dataprotection@ii.co.uk](mailto:dataprotection@ii.co.uk).

## Collection of information

When you are on our website

When you log onto our website, we will automatically log certain information about how you are using the website. This may include the URL that you came from, your IP address and the pages that you visited. To find out more read our [cookie policy](https://www.moneywise.co.uk/use-cookies).

## Competitions, information enquiries and offers

If you enter a competition, we may use your personal information to manage any competition entries you submit, validate such competition entries, and send you any prizes you may win.

If you sign up to receive magazine offers, we will use your personal information to send you the offer.

If you request information from an advertiser via our enquiry service the details needed to supply you with the information you request will be provided to the advertiser.

## Newsletters

We offer e-mail newsletters which can be registered for in isolation or alongside magazine offers. E-mail addresses submitted will be held in an independent database and used to send these regular newsletters. It is possible to unsubscribe from the newsletters at any time. Occasionally we will also send you featured products or services from our carefully selected partners, you can unsubscribe from our commercial emails at any time and receive only newsletters.

## Surveys

Moneywise on occasion runs market research surveys, including but not limited to the annual Customer Service survey and the annual Home Finances survey. Data submitted is provided voluntarily and is held anonymously and cannot be linked back to an individual, it is used solely to produce general analysis of market trends on a grouped basis.

We collect address details and e-mail details at the end of the survey as a separate process to enable free copies of a magazine to be supplied or e-mail newsletters to be delivered.

## Aggregated statistics

We may share your personal data with a third-party auditing organisation (ABC) so they can verify aggregated statistics about circulation and usage of our products or review our policies, processes and procedures for compliance with relevant standards. You can view their privacy policy by following [this link](http://www.abc.org.uk/privacy-policy). 

## Cookies

We use cookies to manage your experience and to measure the use of our website. By using the site you are giving consent to our use of cookies and 3rd party use of cookies. You can find more information including details on how to manage your settings on our [Use of cookies](https://www.moneywise.co.uk/info/use-of-cookies) page.

## Where we store your information

Personal Information may be transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) in order to perform the Services. We will ensure that appropriate controls are in place to ensure your Personal Information is processed and retained in a secure manner which is equivalent to those required within the EEA.

In addition, if you put Personal Information on publicly available parts of the Site, this will be accessible to persons in countries outside the European Economic Area, which may not have data protection laws as comprehensive as those that exist in the European Economic Area.

## Information sharing and disclosure

Moneywise will share personal information with carefully selected third parties in order to maintain the service and to other businesses within our Group for the purpose of informing you of other financial product and services. We will not sell, trade or rent your personal information to others unless you have given us your permission.

On our site you are publicly identified by your user name. If you choose your full name as your username, you have voluntarily disclosed that information to the wider community. If you provide information in your public profile, it will be made public so please consider the details that you are sharing.

We regard our databases of customer information (which will include your Personal Information) as a valuable asset. Should we sell or transfer any of our business assets this may include the sale or transfer of such databases of information to third parties. In addition, such a transfer or sale may mean that your Personal Information is transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area.

Please note that we reserve the right to access and disclose individually identifiable information to comply with applicable laws and lawful government requests, to operate our systems properly and to protect both ourselves and our users.

## Security

We take all reasonable care in the collection, storage, processing and disclosure of your personal data and have implemented internal security procedures to minimise the risk that unauthorised parties will be able to access and misuse the information. However, the internet is an open medium and we cannot guarantee that any information you send to us by email or via our website will not be intercepted or tampered with.

## Children’s information

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children.

## Your rights

You have the following rights (unless exemptions apply), which can be exercised by contacting our Data Protection Officer using the details provided below.

The right:

  * to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes;
  * to access personal information held about you and to obtain a copy of it;
  * to prevent any processing of a record of personal data that is causing or is likely to cause unwarranted and substantial damage or distress to you or another individual;
  * to obtain the rectification or completion of records of personal data which are inaccurate or incomplete;
  * to restrict or object to the processing of your personal data and to request its erasure under certain circumstances. We will not be able to erase personal data where we have a legal obligation to retain such data;
  * in certain circumstances, to receive your personal data, which you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly-used and machine readable format and the right to transmit that data to another data controller without hindrance, or to have that personal data transmitted to another data controller, where technically feasible; and
  * to lodge a complaint about the way in which your personal data is being shared with a supervisory authority.

If you have any queries concerning your personal information please contact us by writing to:

The Data Protection Officer  
Interactive Investor Services Limited  
Exchange Court  
Duncombe Street  
Leeds, LS1 4AX
